“创始吸血鬼”前情提要
DAVlNA: Previously on The Originals...
这座城市曾经是我的家
我要夺回来
This town was my home once.
I want it back.
我希望你帮我夺回纽奥良
让他们眼睁睁看着
I want you to help take New Orleans
from under all of their noses,
而且我有一个内应
and I have someone on the inside.
我需要你的帮助
SOPHlE: I need something from you
好让女巫们完成收获祭
so that the witches
can complete the Harvest.
我需要一名强大女巫的遗骨来献祭
I need to consecrate the remains
of a powerful witch.
她叫莎莉丝特杜博
你们有一个共同的朋友
Her name is Celeste Dubois.
You and she have a friend in common.
以利亚
HAYLEY: Elijah.
仪式没有完成
The Harvest is incomplete.
如果没有完成，就都结束了
我们的法力都会逐渐消逝
If they don't finish it, it's over.
All our power will drain away.
我们的法力会消亡
Our magic fades.
接受祭品，以示吾等之信仰
Accept this offering
as a sign of our faith.
每一个死去的女孩
会将她的力量释放到下一个女孩身上
DAVlNA: Every girl who died
released her power onto the next.
我是最后一个
所以我拥有了全部的力量
When I was the last one,
I suddenly had all of it.
还是个艺术家，真不错
MARCEL: An artist, huh? That's cool.
- 这些画，是什么？
- 她称之为邪恶
-These drawings, what are they?
-She called them evil.
我的天啊
HAYLEY: Oh, my God.
你好，莎莉丝特
Hello, Celeste.
意大利人称之为“巫婆”
ELlJAH: The Italians call them "Strega".
西非的约鲁巴人称之为“阿谢”
The Yoruba of West Africa
call them "aje",
意思是“巫母”
meaning "mother".
我母亲故乡的人称之为“黑克萨”
Where my mother as from,
they called them "hexa".
而我们则称其为“女巫”
And here we call them witch.
几世纪以来，吸血鬼与女巫对战
也与女巫并肩作战
Over the centuries, vampires fought them
and fought beside them,
与其共寝，也将其烧杀
bedded them and burned them.
无论是敌是友
Whether adversary or ally,
女巫都是不可小观的力量
they have been a force
to be reckoned with.
她们祖传的魔法维护着这城市的稳定
Their ancestral magic anchors this city.
世上从没有如此强大的女巫
直到戴维娜出现
There's never been
one all-powerful witch until Davina.
她现在就在走廊那一头
KLAUS: Who is now
tucked in safe and sound
在我的保护下安然无恙
down the hall under my protection.
你的莎莉丝特真是漂亮
Your Celeste was quite beautiful,
也象征着邪恶
and a portent of evil,
据我们这里情绪不稳的画家所说
according to our volatile artist
in residence.
是，也许黛维娜弄错了
把强大的能量当成邪恶
Yes. Perhaps Davina's mistaken
what she calls evil for power.
莎莉丝特在当时确实非常强大
Celeste was certainly very powerful
in her day.
但她已经死了两百多年了
But she's been dead for over 200 years.
我不明白为什么会有这些素描
I don't understand
why all these sketches now.
女巫做的任何事又是为什么呢？
Why does any witch do anything?
走开
(SCREECHlNG) Go away!
别这样，你一定饿了
你都没吃过东西，自从…
Come on. You got to be starving.
You haven't eaten since...
自从你的好朋友杀了我的好朋友是吗？
Since your best friend
killed my best friend?
黛维娜，对于提姆那孩子发生的事
我感到遗憾
Davina, I'm sorry
about what happened to this kid, Tim.
我才遗憾你竟然不痛恨
克劳斯的所作所为
I'm sorry you don't hate Klaus
for what he did
也不打算让他付出代价
or want to make him pay.
他总会为他的行为付出代价的
不管以什么方式
He'll pay for what he did,
one way or the other.
但现在，我只想跟你讲和
But right now,
I just want to make peace with you.
为什么？
Why?
这样我们就可以成为
快乐的自我毁灭的一家人吗？
So we can be one, big,
happy Frankenstein family?
进展得才顺利嘛
Well, that's going well.
如果你要赢得那女孩的信任
If you were trying
to win the girl's trust,
或许毒死她的真爱
不是个那么好的方法
perhaps poisoning her one true love
was not the most splendid idea.
你还能找出更多不凑巧被我杀死的人
可以用来给我打脸吗？
Are there any inopportune deaths
you'd like to wave in my face?
给我一个月时间
我给你列张名单
Give me a month.
I'll get you a list.
不管是老的少的，死的活的
女巫都这么惹人厌
Young, old, dead, or alive,
witches are a pain the ass.
黛维娜，黛维娜
Davina. Davina!
怎么这么吵？
What's with all the racket?
我的天啊
Bloody hell.
以利亚？
Elijah?
有件事情你得知道
There's something you need to know.
这是怎么回事？
What the hell is going on?
是黛维娜
Davina.
片名：创始吸血鬼（第一季）
剧名：洪水将至
主演：约瑟夫摩根
嘿，你在玩什么把戏？
Hey. What kind of game
do you think you're playing?
我只说离间这屋子里的人
主演：丹尼尔吉利斯
I said disrupt the household,
不是摧毁整个城市
主演：丹尼尔吉利斯
not destroy the whole city.
不是我干的
I didn't do it.
我不是故意的，我…
Not on purpose. I...
我不知道我怎么了
主演：克莱儿荷特
I don't know what's wrong with me.
这太疯狂了
KLAUS: This is madness.
一个16岁的少女
主演：菲比托金
How can a 16-year-old girl
怎么能使整个法语区剧烈见动？
主演：菲比托金
shake the entire French Quarter?
我见过她使教堂见动
主演：查尔斯麦可戴维斯
I seen her rock the church,
但我从没见过这样的事
主演：查尔斯麦可戴维斯
but not anything like this.
她在阁楼的时候你怎么控制住她的？
How did you control her
when she was in the attic?
我不必控制她
主演：丹妮耶拉皮纳达
I didn't have to,
但那时我没杀了她男朋友
主演：丹妮耶拉皮纳达
but I never killed her boyfriend.
是，关于这个我们不是讨论过了吗？
主演：莉雅派普斯
Yes, yes.
We've been over this part already.
问题是，以她现在的状态
主演：丹妮儿坎贝尔
The point is, in her present state
她就是个无用的工具
主演：丹妮儿坎贝尔
she's useless as a tool
无法对抗女巫
against the witches.
她不是什么工具，她身体出问题了
She's not a tool.
Something's wrong with her.
她体内能量超载，她控制不了
She has too much power
that she cannot control.
我们都知道那能量有多强大
That much we already knew.
但为什么这些能量
会如此激烈地爆发出来呢？
But why is it manifesting itself
in such an aggressive manner?
你去哪？
Where are you going?
这是女巫问题
就找个女巫问问
This is witch business.
Let's ask a witch.
你要去找苏菲
You're going to see Sophie.
你没必要偷听
我从来不瞒你任何事
You don't have to eavesdrop.
I keep nothing from you.
是，我也不想隐瞒你任何事
Well, I don't wanna
keep anything from you either.
如果你要出去见苏菲
And if you're going out
to see Sophie,
那么有件事我得告诉你
then there's something
that you should know.
她打电话给我，找我帮忙
制片：兰斯安德森
She called me
and asked me for a favor.
她跟我保证会帮我解除马赛尔
She promised me
that she would help break the curse
在我族人身上下的诅咒
而我要提供一些讯息给她作为交换
that Marcel put on my people
in exchange for some information.
我当时没多想
I didn't think anything of it.
但现在黛维娜画了那些
莎莉丝特的画…
But then Davina started doing
those pictures of Celeste--
不管是什么事
你必须告诉我
Whatever this is,
you have to tell me.
制片：邦妮怀斯
苏菲想找到莎莉丝特的遗骸
Sophie wanted to find
Celeste's remains.
所以我就…
So I
翻了你的日记
编剧：玛格丽特麦金泰尔
went through your journals,
找到了你埋葬她的位置
编剧：贷安艾德穆强
and found out where you buried her,
然后把位置告诉了她
导演：莱斯利里布曼
and then I told her.
我知道这样做很蠢很八婆
I know it was stupid
and it was snoopy,
我应该事先问过你
and I should have just asked you.
说句话好吗？
求求你
Please say something. Please.
她想死后可以求得安宁
She wanted to be left in peace.
当女巫的遗骸被献祭时
When a witch's remains are consecrated,
其能量会增进其他女巫的法力
that power fuels
the rest of their community.
莎莉丝特不想别人找到她的遗骸
Celeste did not want her remains
to be found.
她要我答应她把她埋在
不会被人发现的地方
She made me promise to bury her
where she would not be found.
你不仅侵犯了我的隐私
还让我违背了自己的誓言
You not only violated my privacy,
you have broken my promise to her.
我以为就只是些骨骸，以利亚
I thought they were just bones, Elijah.
你如果真是这么想
If you truly believed that,
那为什么不亲自问我她在哪里？
why didn't you ask me
where to find her?
如果这是晚餐，那我免了
Ugh. If that's dinner, I pass.
苏菲，你去哪了？
Sophie, where have you been?
简而言之，盗墓去了
Short answer, grave robbing.
放下你手头的事情
我们要找黛维娜了
Stop whatever you're doing.
We need to find Davina.
我找到完成仪式的方法了
I figured out a way
to complete the Harvest.
什么？怎么做？
What? How?
我们需要
借助一位长老的力量，对吧？
We need an elder to do it, right?
我知道怎么成为一个长老
I figured out a way
how to become one.
苏菲，你不可能成为长老的
Soph,
you can't just become an elder.
法力必须由其他长老
That power has to be bestowed
upon you
传授给你，而她们都死了
by the other elders,
all of whom are dead.
懂了吗？
Following my logic?
借监一下前人的经验怎么样？
我查过了
How about follow your history?
I did research.
17 42年，女巫曾遭到大屠杀
所有的长老无一幸免
In 1742, there was a witch massacre
that wiped out all the elders.
所以她们决定女巫中谁能献祭
So they decided whoever consecrated
最强大的女巫遗骸，就能成为长老
the most powerful dead witch
in the community became an elder.
- 这一招很管用
- 有个小问题
-lt worked for them.
-Teeny flaw.
哪位强大的女巫能轮到你来埋？
What powerful witch
is even left for you to bury?
认识一下莎莉丝特玛丽赫兰杜博
Meet Celeste Marie-Helene Dubois.
以利亚米卡森的老情人
Elijah Mikaelson's old lover.
她在18 21年因身为女巫被淹死
She was drowned in 1821
for being a witch.
他埋葬了她，从未告诉任何人地点
He buried her,
never told anyone where.
那你是怎么找到她的？
So how the hell did you find her?
我买通了海莉去翻他的日记
I bribed Hayley to read his journals.
然后把她挖了出来
Then I dug her ass up,
这样我就可以献祭她的遗骸
吸取她的能量
so I could consecrate her bones
and absorb her power.
你还真一点都不失礼啊
That's not disrespectful.
不然呢？我们只有几周去完成仪式了
Yeah, well, we only have a couple
more weeks to complete the Harvest.
苏菲，我知道时间不多了…
Soph, I'm aware of our deadline.
如果我们失败了
女巫在这座城市就玩完了
If we fail, the witches are done for
in this town.
我们就永远没有法力了
Our power will fade for good.
那些牺牲的女孩永远不会复活
Those girls sacrificed
will never resurrect.
我的侄女也不会
My niece will never come back.
如果挖出些骇人的骨头能让莫妮克复活
If digging up some creepy old bones
means I get Monique back,
我才管不了那么多呢
I don't care about anything else.
我却得管
ELlJAH: I happen to care.
跟我来
You're coming with me.
你偷的正是
So you have stolen the remains
of the very person
黛维娜画了数月的人的遗骸
that Davina's been drawing
for months.
能解释一下这惊人的巧合吗？
Would you care to explain
this startling coincidence?
我解释不了
I can't.
我一直都不知道
莎莉丝特杜博是谁直到我…
I didn't even know
who Celeste Dubois was until l...
是黛维娜吗？
Was that Davina?
她最近养成的好习惯
Charming little habit she's developed.
- 那今天的地震呢？
- 也是黛维娜
-And the earthquake I felt today?
-REBEKAH: Also Davina.
而且她现在还喜欢吐泥土
And she's taken to vomiting dirt.
我们麻烦大了
We have a huge problem.
我以为时间还充格
I thought that we had more time,
但看来必须马上完成仪式
but we need to complete
the Harvest now.
正中你意你当然说得轻松了
Said the desperate witch,
conveniently.
我说真的
I'm serious.
刚刚的地震正是
That earthquake you just felt,
我们即将大难临头的征兆
a preview of the disaster movie
that is about to hit us.
我们凭什么相信你？
Why should we believe you?
你见过黛维娜，知道她的事情
You've met Davina,
you know her story.
数月来，她身上一直汇聚着
For months now,
she's been holding all the power
在仪式上牺牲的其他三个女孩的力量
of the three girls sacrificed
in the Harvest ritual.
那股力量本该从她体内流出
回归大地
A force that was meant to flow
through her and back into the earth.
一个人是不可能控制住
那么强大的力量的
One person was never meant
to hold that much power.
那会把她毁掉
也会毁掉我们
It's tearing her apart,
and it will take us down with it.
我们得着手准备了
KLAUS: We need to prepare.
照苏菲德弗罗所言
黛维娜的自毁之路
According to Sophie Deveraux,
as Davina self-destructs,
会经历四个阶段
she'll cycle through four stages
其代表了组成仪式的四大元素
that represent the four elements
that bound together the Harvest.
- 地震算吗？
- 是的
-The earthquake?
-Yes.
- 首先是土
- 接着是风
-Earth stage comes first.
-Then comes wind.
每个阶段都会比之前的更猛烈
And since each stage
is more intense than the last,
你将把这整个地方都掀了
Iet's just say
you'll blow the roof off this place.
风之后是水
Then after the wind is water.
雨水、洪水，有多糟？
Rain, flood.
How bad?
非常糟糕
但还不是最糟的
Quite bad actually,
but that's not the worst of it.
最后是火
因为是最后一个阶段
The last stage is fire,
and since it's the last...
它将是最严重的
It will be by far the worst.
但我可不想看到这个城市
在我手上烧成灰烬
But I didn't take over this town
to watch it burn to the ground.
你能阻止，对吧？
You can stop this, right?
是的，但你不会喜欢我的做法
Yes, but you're not gonna like how.
- 她们要完成仪式
- 不
-They want to complete the Harvest.
-No!
女巫说你会复活的
The witches say
you'll be resurrected.
她们说谎
她们为了得到想要的口不择言
They're liars! They'll say anything
to get what they want.
和马赛尔一样
和你一样
Just like Marcel.
Just like you.
黛维娜，你可能觉得我不在乎你
但你错了
Davina, you may think I don't care
about you, but you're wrong.
我知道因为别人犯的错
I know what it's like to have
your life stripped away from you
而被剥夺生命是什么感觉
because of other people's
bad decisions.
你觉得我怎么变成吸血鬼的？
How do you think I became a vampire?
你说服了我的弟弟妹妹
但还没说服我们
You've convinced my siblings.
You have yet to convince us.
我们没时间了
SOPHlE: We don't have time to waste.
第一个预示已经过去
The first sign's already come
and gone.
- 那就治好她
- 她已经治不好了
-So fix her.
-She can't be fixed.
那是什么？
What is that?
你情绪越激动
情况会越快恶化
The more upset you become,
the faster you deteriorate.
- 我用魅惑弄了些镇定剂来
- 不，不要
-I compelled up some sedative.
-No, no, no!
只要你保持冷静
就能继续活着，黛维娜
We keep you calm,
we keep you alive, Davina.
住手
她救不了了
SOPHlE: She can't be saved.
这事不会止于地震预示
This will not stop at the earth sign.
如果你们再等下去
And if you wait it out,
能活着讨论的只剩你们这些死不了的了
you immortals will be the only ones
left to argue about it.
不要，拜托
No, please!
不要，求求你
你们现在信了吗？
Convinced now?
镇定剂的药量太多了
ELlJAH: We sedated her too heavily.
如果这是她镇定的样子
我还真讨厌见她其他的样子
KLAUS: Well, if this is her sedated,
I'd hate to see her otherwise.
我们都同意黛维娜必须牺牲
We all agreed
that Davina must be sacrificed.
没必要再让她搞得天翻地覆了
There's no need to let her blow the roof
off our heads in the meantime.
不行，我不许你动她
No way!
You're not touching her!
好吧，那一拳算我让你的
Okay, I'll let you have that one.
马赛尔，我也很不希望黛维娜受伤
Marcel, no one wishes to see Davina
come to harm less than l.
但这件事不是等待能解决的
But there is no scenario here
in which we simply wait this out.
她必须要死的
She's going to die.
说这话的女巫可把大家耍得团团转
According to Sophie, the witch
who screwed over everybody here.
收获祭确实起了作用，直到被中断
The Harvest was working
before it was stopped.
苏菲原本不信这一切
If a non-believer
like Sophie Deveraux
现在都能相信这些女孩会复活
can come to have faith
these girls will be resurrected,
那我也选择相信
then l, also, am a believer.
我从收获祭上救下了黛维娜
现在你却叫我把她拱手相让？
I saved Davina from the Harvest,
now you want me to hand her over?
你难道以为我愿意吗？
Do you think
that I'm happy about this?
如果女巫们完成收获祭
她们不仅会重新得到法力
If the witches complete the Harvest,
not only do they regain their power.
我们也会失去对付她们的武器
We lose our weapon against them.
地震，我姑且把它当作是可怕的巧合
The earthquake I was willing
to chalk up to hideous coincidence.
但这大风呢？
But these winds?
如果黛维娜不牺牲
If Davina is not sacrificed,
刚刚见动过的每一寸土地
现在刮起的每一粒砂石
then every inch of earth that shook,
everything blowing about now
都会被洪水淹没
被烈火吞噬
will soon be drenched in water
and consumed by fire.
- 现在你在乎这个城市了
- 我们应该在乎，是我们建造了它
-Now you care about the city.
-We ought to. We built it.
我们都曾两次目睹这里被大火夷为平地
And we all saw it
burnt to the ground twice.
我不会再让那样的事发生
我说得够清楚吗？
I will not let that happen again.
Do I make myself clear?
清楚了
Yeah.
你不怎么喜欢人类，是吗
尼克劳斯？
-Not a people person, are you, Niklaus?
胡说，我最爱人类了
-Nonsense. I love people.
我这就去警告那几个比较杰出的人类
Just on my way
to warn a couple of prominent ones
以防状况一发不可收拾
in case the weather
gets out of hand.
如果你喜欢做外交言
If you fancy yourself
as plus diplomatique,
也可以跟我一起去
perhaps you'd like to come along.
不，苏菲德弗罗
很快就会献祭莎莉丝特的遗骸
No, soon Sophie Deveraux shall be
consecrating Celeste's remains.
尽管她的行为应受谴责
我还是应该去悼念一下
Her actions are reprehensible,
still I should pay my respects.
- 你有时间吗？
- 正打算出去
-Hey. Do you have a minute?
-ELlJAH: Just on my way out.
我们俩谁比较亲民来着？
Which one of us
is the people person again?
那没用的
Fat lot of good that will do.
- 我可没时间跟你寒暄
- 很好，我也一样
-SOPHlE; I don't have time to socialize.
-REBEKAH: Good. Neither do l.
等你在圣地埋入女巫遗骸后
When you're done burying
your witchy bits on sacred ground,
你准备好进行收获祭了吗？
are you prepared
to perform the Harvest?
你知道你要割开一个女孩的喉咙吧
You do realize
you have to slit a girl's throat.
而她是个很可爱的女孩
A very sweet girl as it turns out.
如果这样能够换回我的侄女莫妮克
我什么都做得出来
If it gets my niece Monique back,
I can handle anything.
你来这的真正目的是什么？
Why are you really here?
一切结束之后
When all this is done,
黛维娜将复活
女巫们的法力也将恢复
after Davina is resurrected
and the witches get their power back,
那时你将要做出一个决定
you'll have a decision to make.
洗耳恭听
Enlighten me.
一个拥有全部法力的女巫可以
与一个吸血鬼势均力敌
A witch at her full power can trade body
blows with a vampire punch for punch.
相信我，我知道
Believe me, I know.
我也知道
能跟吸血鬼公平对抗的感觉一定不错
So do l. Would be nice
to have a fair fight for a change.
公平可帮不了你什么，亲爱的
Fair only gets you so far, love.
有聪明的头脑才能走得更远
Clever gets you further.
这事结束后，马赛尔仍在这里
克劳斯也是
After this, Marcel will still be here,
and so will Klaus.
他们的手段有多卑鄙
你比任何人都清楚
And you know better than anyone
that those two don't fight fair.
如果要让他们不再掌权
你会需要一个真祖站在你这边
You are going to need an Original on your
side and I'm gonna need a witch on mine
我也需要一个女巫的支援
if we're gonna stop those two
from running things.
我没听错吧？
你为什么要跟我结盟？
Am I missing something?
Why would you side with me?
有时候，重要的并不是盟友是谁
Sometimes, what's more important
is not who you're siding with,
而是谁是你的敌人
but who you're siding against.
不要，不要
DAVlNA: No, No!
放开我！住手！
Let go of me! Stop it!
有我在
I got you.
我会保护你
I got you right here.
嘿，克劳斯说不要动她
Hey, Klaus said not to.
我受够了对他唯命是从
I'm done caring what Klaus says.
你没必要来这里
You don't have to be here for this.
苏菲准备献祭还需要一些时间
It's gonna take some time for Sophie
to prepare for her consecration.
我有时间
I have time.
这是我欠她的
I owe her this.
你想说说原因吗？
Care to elaborate why?
你有没有经历过一些事
非常…
Have you ever experienced
something so...
刻骨铭心，美妙无比
...profoundly wonderful,
而一旦失去却让你难以承受？
that when it was taken from you,
your life felt unbearable?
嗯，我知道那种感觉
Yes, I have felt that.
我知道那种痛是什么滋味
And I've got the scars to prove it.
我相信当你深爱着一个人
而那人也同样爱你
I believe that when you love someone
and that person loves you in return,
你会变得格外脆弱
you're uniquely vulnerable.
他们有一种特殊的力量
能将你伤得体无完肤
They have a power to hurt you
that's like nothing else.
蕾贝卡
Rebekah.
- 他把那女孩带走了
- 谁带走了她？
-He's taken the girl.
-ELlJAH: Who has?
那个该死的马赛尔
Bloody, bloody Marcel!
你还曾想过跟这种出卖朋友的人私奔呢
And you wanted to run off,
start a life with this back stabber.
就在事发前两秒
你不是还跟他鬼混在一起吗？
Says the man who was shacking up
with him not two seconds before all this.
好吧，如果想找到他们
我们必须分头行动
Okay, we need to divide and conquer
if we're gonna stand a chance.
他可能去任何地方
He could have gone anywhere.
我正和莎宾在一起
或许我们可以试试用定位咒
Well, I'm here with Sabine.
We could try a locator spell?
我去神父那看看
他们说不定会在教堂
I'll talk to the priest.
They might even be at the church.
毕竟这是我们最不可能去搜索的地方
It's the last place we'd think
to look for them, right?
好，你去搜索教堂
我去搜索其他地方
Okay, you check the church,
I'll check everywhere else.
你在干什么？
What are you doing?
我正准备把这些拿去…
I was gonna take these to the--
如果你要说“河口
If you say, "bayou,"
我现在就找个舒适的地牢把你扔进去
I will find a nice comfy dungeon
and throw you in it.
今晚不适合外出
This is not the night
to be out there.
对所有人来说都是
...for anyone.
但有些人别无选择
But some people don't have a choice.
好吧
Right.
把这些拿着跟我走
Grab that lot and come with me.
吾将此遗骸献与大地
I consecrate these bones
to the earth.
先祖英灵，听吾召唤
Ancestors, hear me.
吾将此遗骸献与大地
I consecrate these bones
to the earth.
先祖英灵，听吾召唤
Ancestors, hear me.
- 这不管用
- 一点她的踪迹都没有吗？
-This isn't working.
-She's nowhere to be found.
不，应该是说她无处不在
No.
It's more like she's everywhere.
她的法力正在流失
She's hemorrhaging magic.
这意味着我们的时间不多了
我们一定要找到她
We have less time than we thought.
We have got to find her.
- 但我完全不知道她在哪里
- 请你集中精力
-I have no clue where she is.
-Please concentrate.
再试一次
Try again.
- 我不会伤害你的
- 我不相信你
-I'm not gonna hurt you.
-I don't believe you!
你和他们一样都想杀死我
You want to kill me
just like everyone else.
是我在你身上施了保护咒，小黛
I'm the one who put
a protection spell on you, D.
所以提姆死了，你却能活下来
That's why Tim's dead
and you're not.
你再扔我之前，先听我说
And before you throw me again,
如果我知道你的朋友会遭过不测
if I had known anything
was gonna happen to your friend,
我也会一样保护他的
I would have protected him, too.
- 是你救了我吗？
- 是的
-You're the one who saved me?
-Yeah.
但如今帮我施咒的女巫
和他们结成了同盟
But now the witch who did the spell
is in league with the rest of them,
所以我必须带你走
so I had to take you away.
- 这样你又能拿我当武器了吗？
- 我只是想保护你的安全
-So you could use me as a weapon?
-I'm trying to keep you safe.
黛维娜，看着我
Davina, look at me.
是我搞砸了
I messed up.
你的这些能力确实带给我许多优势
All this power that you have,
it gave me an advantage.
它让我得以惩罚那些女巫
也让我统治这个城市
It helped me punish the witches,
and it let me run the city,
而我把它看得太重了
and I let that mean too much.
但这一切都过去了
我们都是幸存者
All right, but that's over with now.
One survivor to another.
我发誓，现在我只想让你活着
All I want to do is keep you alive,
I swear.
我好害怕
我不知道自己是怎么了
I'm scared.
I don't know what's wrong with me.
你不是一个人
我们会解决这一切的
You're not alone.
We'll fix this.
- 你不会让他们伤害我？
- 不会的，没人能伤害你
-You won't let them hurt me?
-No. Nobody's gonna touch you.
你之前拿来的
我们都还没用完呢，克劳斯
We still haven't gone through all
that you've already provided, Klaus.
这些不是我带来的
Well, this newest bit isn't from me.
- 你真善良
- 我叫海莉
-That's very kind of you.
-Hayley.
这些人是？
And these people are?
我请基兰神父给他们提供庇护
I asked Father Kieran
to give them shelter.
他总是抑制不住自己想做善事的欲望
He suffers from an incessant desire
to do good.
但现在我要你帮个忙
马赛尔和黛维娜失踪了
But now I need you to be useful.
Marcel and Davina have disappeared.
从你目瞪口呆的表情看来
I assume,
from the stupefied look on your face,
他们应该没躲在你的阁楼里
they haven't sought refuge
in your attic.
- 没有，那都是过去的事了
- 那就充分利用你的资源
-No, those days are gone.
-Then energize your resources.
我不需要提醒你
找到他们有多重要吧
I don't need to remind you
how important it is they be found.
我明白
Yeah.
这些人，他们都是狼人
These people, they're werewolves.
神父说是你捐献了这些食物
And the priest,
he said that you donated the food.
你在帮助他们吗？
You're helping them?
他们不是你的族人，而是我的
都是很久以前的事了
They're not your werewolves.
They're my clan from very far back.
如今他们陷入困境
They've fallen upon hard times.
他们的困境激发出了
我乐善好施的一面
And their plight has brought out
the philanthropist in me.
我能说什么呢？
想必是受以利亚的影响吧
What can I say?
Must be Elijah's influence.
什么叫做你的族人？
What do you mean your clan?
我和他们的血管里
流着同样的血液
The blood that runs in their veins
runs in mine.
还有我们的孩子也是
And in our child's.
这个家族真是越来越复杂了
This family gets more complicated
by the second.
听着，海莉
给你一句
Listen, Hayley.
Word of advice.
与以利亚相处的忠告
别跟我一样
When dealing with Elijah,
don't do as I do.
直接道歉就好
Just apologize.
尽管他在很多方面都有所成就
但他最擅长的，是宽恕
He's accomplished in many things,
but he is a master of forgiveness.
接近了
Okay.
找到了，她在河边
She's somewhere near the river.
- 没办法更精确了
- 也算有进展了，是个开始
-I can't be more specific.
-It's something. It's a start.
没有用
It didn't work.
我试图献祭她
吸取她的法力
I tried to consecrate her
and absorb her magic,
- 但什么都没有
- 我不明白
-but there's nothing there.
-ELlJAH: I don't understand.
女巫的法力在献祭前
都会蕴藏在遗骨中
A witch's magic is infused
in her bones until consecrated.
那就是有人已经取走了那些法力
因为那里什么都没有
Well, someone's already taken it
because there's nothing there.
- 一定有别的办法
- 没有别的办法
-Has to be another way.
-There is no other way.
除非你还知道有其他
超强女巫的遗骨
Unless you know
of some super-powerful dead witch
没被献祭过
whose bones
were never consecrated...
都结束了
...it's over.
确实还有别人
There is someone else actually.
我母亲
My mother.
虽然过了一千年
但你终究还是疯了
It's taken 1,000 years,
but you've finally gone mad.
- 我们的母亲？
- 是，我们深爱的母亲
-Our own mother?
-Yes, our beloved mother.
被尼克劳斯充满爱意地
放在地下室的棺材里
who Niklaus has affectionately
placed in a coffin in his basement.
虽然没插匕首，但也死得很透彻
Not daggered but quite dead.
她确实曾经试图杀了我们
Well, she did try to kill us all.
那我们这次就利用一下她
再让她安息吧
Well, I say we put her to use,
put her to rest once and for all.
如果我们现在把我们的母亲
埋在她后代所拥有的土地中
Now, if we bury our mother on land
owned by one of her descendents,
她就成了纽奥良女巫
she becomes a New Orleans witch.
我们身为她的家人
就可以共享祖传的法力
And we as her family
share in that ancestral magic.
我们是吸血鬼，以利亚
We're vampires, Elijah.
我们不能施法
也没办法拥有土地
We can't practice magic
or own property for that matter.
- 没错，关于施法的问题…
- 这由我来负责
-With regard to practicing magic....
-That's where I come in.
在他们埋葬了母亲以后
他们可以把她所有法力传递给我
After they bury their mother,
they can channel her power to me.
只是由于需要传递艾丝塔的法力
Only hitch is,
as conduits of Esther's magic,
他们必须参与收获祭
they need to participate
in the Harvest.
至于拥有土地…
And as for owning property...
我们母亲的后代也没有都死光
...not all of our mother's
descendents are dead.
- 孩子
- 那个孩子
-The baby.
教区税务稽查办公室
离法语区不远
The parish tax assessor's office
is just steps outside of the quarter.
种植园现在在海莉名下
Hayley now holds the title
to the plantation.
如果我们把母亲埋在那里
然后献祭那片土地
If we bury our mother there
and we consecrate those grounds,
我们就可以完成收获祭仪式
we can finish the Harvest ritual.
你真是太聪明了，以利亚
You're a bit of
a mad genius, Elijah.
- 算我一份
- 难道我是唯一有理智的人吗？
-Count me in.
-Am I the only one thinking?
我们的母亲是史上最强大的女巫
Our mother was
the most powerful witch in history.
如果我们埋葬了她，就等于把她的力量
拱手送给了我们的敌人
If we bury her, we hand that power
to our enemies to use against us.
考虑到现在这种情况
我们也没有别的选择了，蕾贝卡
Given our circumstances,
I hardly see that we have a choice.
我不知道我操心这个干嘛
反正你们还是会按照自己的意愿行事
I don't know why I bother.
You two will just do what you want anyway.
不，我们必须意见一致
No, our decision must be unanimous.
- 这不是搞什么民主
- 你说得很对
-This is not a democracy.
-You're quite right.
这是家务事
This is family.
水
Water.
下一个预示开始了，蕾贝卡
The next sign's begun.
Rebekah?
兵来将档，水来土掩吧
Kill a demon today,
face the devil tomorrow.
算我一份
Count me in.
没有母亲怎么能算家庭聚会呢？
Well, this is no family reunion
without our mother.
我去把她请过来
I'll fetch her.
你利用黛维娜复仇的宏伟计划
就到此为止了吗？
So much for your grand schemes
of using Davina for revenge.
生存第一
推翻我哥哥的计划再议
Survival first,
plot to overthrow my brother second.
马赛尔会把珍贵的东西藏在哪里？
Where would Marcel
hide something precious to him?
你觉得我会把它供出来
这样你就能把我丢在这里腐烂吗？
You think I'm gonna offer that up
so you can leave me here to rot?
水往低处流
Water runs downhill.
你觉得我没溺过水
不知道那有多痛苦吗？
You think I have to have drowned
to know how much that will suck.
火还会杀死吸血鬼呢，提艾里
And fire kills vampires, Thierry.
你觉得烧成灰就好受了吗？
You think burning to ash
will be pleasant?
听着，我没有放弃你
Look, I am not forsaking you.
我答应你一定会信守承诺
I promise to live up
to my end of the deal.
等一切都结束我一定会救你出来的
I'll get you out of here
when all of this is done.
告诉我马赛尔会去哪里
Just tell me where Marcel would go.
码头附近有个地方
There's a place by the docks.
如果我能再等几周
If I can just wait it out
a few more weeks.
- 帮帮我，求求你
- 我会的
-Help me, please.
-I will.
等这一切都结束
我会做我早该做的事
And when it's over,
I'll do what I should have done.
把你送出城
Get you out of town.
我做了个梦，提姆没死
I had a dream that Tim wasn't dead,
他演奏了一首为我写的歌
and he played a song
that he wrote for me.
还亲了我
And he kissed me.
我们都只是普通人
And we were just normal.
听起来是个美梦
That sounds like a beautiful dream.
你来这里干什么？
What are you doing here?
但那只是个梦
But it was just a dream.
出去
Get out!
这会要了她的命
你的顽固会害死她的
This is killing her.
Your stubbornness will kill her.
我答应过她会为她而战
我不会言而无信的
I promised her I'd fight for her.
I'm not breaking that promise.
没人叫你停止战斗
No one is asking you not to fight.
你是这个女孩唯一的家人
You're the only family
that this girl has.
你欠她的，去为她而战，让她活下去
You owe it to her
to fight for her to live.
你找到他们了吗？
Did you find them?
他会带她来吗？
Will he bring her?
他会的
He'll bring her.
你们都准备好了吗？
Are you ready to do this?
永远在一起
Always and forever.
完成了
It is done.
马赛尔，没事的
Marcel, it's okay.
不，我辜负了你
No. I failed you.
不管是否这么做，我都会死
I'll die whether I do this or not.
现在唯一的选择就是
是否要让所有人一起陪葬
I mean, now the only option is,
is whether I take everyone with me.
如果这么想的话
不做还真有点自私
If you look at it that way,
it's kind of selfish not to do it.
一定还有别的办法
不该是这样的结局
There has to be another way.
This is not how it ends.
如果就是呢？
And if it is?
如果这就是我的一生
If this is all I have...
那我已经拥有很多了
...I've had a lot.
我有莫妮克，我有提姆
I had Monique, and I had Tim.
还有你从认识我的那刻开始
就一直坚定地守护着我
And I had someone who fought for me
from the moment you met me.
黛维娜
Davina.
许多人即使活到一百岁
都得不到这一切
Most people don't get that
even if they live to be 100.
马赛尔，我准备好了
Marcel, I'm ready.
火
Fire.
- 你相信收获祭吗？
- 我相信
-Do you believe in the Harvest?
-I believe.
收获之后将迎来收割
After the Harvest comes the reaping.
她们献祭已完成并被接受
Their sacrifice is made and accepted.
我们召唤长老
复活被选中者
We call upon our elders
to resurrect your chosen ones.
我们召唤长老
复活被选中者
We call upon our elders
to resurrect your chosen ones.
复活被选中者
Resurrect your chosen ones.
拜托
Please.
我恳求你们
I beg.
不
SOPHlE: No.
这样也不能让她起死回生
你知道吗？
-That won't bring her back, you know.
这是你的错
-This is your fault.
我不应该让你接近她
I should have never let you
anywhere near her.
- 马赛尔
- 在你来之前，这个城市一切都很好
-Marcel.
-This city was fine before you came.
我们都很好
We were fine!
黛维娜很安全
她将自己控制得很好
Davina was safe!
She was in control!
如果你没惹她生气
如果你没杀了那个男孩
If you hadn't gotten her worked up,
if you hadn't killed that boy!
对她的死我深感哀悼
但不要失去理智
My condolences the girl is gone,
but don't lose perspective.
我们还有自己的社区
这座城市所有的吸血鬼
We still have our community.
The vampires of this town--
我根本不在乎这些吸血鬼
I don't care about the vampires!
她死了
She is dead!
你听到了吗？
Do you hear me?
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
你也许觉得我一点都不了解你的痛苦
You may think
I know nothing of your grief,
但你错了
but you are wrong.
在我逃离这座城市之后的日子里
我以为你死了
In the days after I fled this city,
I thought you were dead.
好多年我都不敢提起你的名字
It was years
before I could speak your name,
那种失去的感觉格外强烈
so keenly did I feel that loss.
我很遗憾
I'm sorry.
真的很遗憾
- 你打算原谅我了吗？
- 没那么容易的，海莉
-Are you ready to forgive me yet?
-It's not that easy, Hayley.
以利亚，我不该偷看你的日记
Elijah, I was wrong
to go through your journals.
我不该告诉苏菲关于莎莉丝特的事
I was wrong
to tell Sophie about Celeste.
但在经历过今天这一切之后
But after everything
that happened today,
我不明白为什么我们不能放下这件事
I don't know why
we can't see past this.
在所有人中，你最该知道为什么
And you of all people
should know why.
当我在河口高烧不退时
你看到了我的内心
During my fever in the bayou,
you were inside my mind.
- 你知道莎莉丝特在我心中的位置
- 难道不是曾经的位置吗？
-You know what Celeste means to me.
-Don't you mean meant to you?
不是
No.
你知道爱有多么难得吗？
Do you have any idea
how rare love is?
在一千年里，我只遇到过两次
In a thousand years,
I have found it but twice.
一旦我拥有，我就会好好珍惜
And when I have, I have honored it.
我知道承诺对你意义重大，以利亚
I know what a promise
means to you, Elijah.
但那是两百年前的承诺了
But you made it 200 years ago.
而我活在当下
I live the in the now.
如果我感受到了什么，我会马上行动
If I feel something, I act.
如果我渴望什么，我会主动争取
If I want something, I take it.
我不会因为逝者而冷落生者
I won't choose the dead
over the living.
而你为什么要这样呢？
So why are you?
对不起，以利亚
I'm sorry, Elijah.
这一切从一开始就注定是个悲剧
KLAUS: This whole thing was doomed
from the start, you know?
是的，我们拯救了这个城市
Yes, we saved the city.
倒不是说女巫们失去法力不好
I'm not complaining about
the witches losing their power.
但这的确不是我预想的结局
But this did not go down
the way I thought it would.
不过你倒是让我大吃一惊
你今天还真是足智多谋
You surprised me, though.
You were quite resourceful today.
你是怎么在码头找到他们的？
How did you find them
down at the docks?
在法语区可不只你一个人有间谋，尼克
You're not the only one with clever
little spies in the Quarter, Nik.
有时我真觉得自己低估了你，妹妹
Sometimes I think I don't give you
your due, little sister.
我知道以利亚的计划很疯狂
但我真的以为会成功
I knew Elijah's plan was mad,
but I really thought it would work.
我也是
So did l.
我真以为黛维娜会活下来
I was sure Davina would survive.
她那么有生命力
There was so much life in her.
那些法力呢？
What about the power?
四个人本该复活的，但一个都没有
Four were supposed to rise,
and none did.
那些法力去哪了？
Where did all that power go?
- 我们为什么在这里？
- 有人召唤我们
-Why are we here?
-Someone called us forth.
是谁？
Who?
是我
SABlNE: I did.
莎宾，这是为什么？
Sabine! What's the meaning of this?
贝丝蒂娜，这一年来
Bastiana, I've had to endure
people calling me "Sabine"
我都得忍受人们叫我“莎宾”
for almost a year now.
如果你们能叫我的真名，我会很感激的
I'd appreciate it if you'd call me
by my real name.
叫我莎莉丝特
Celeste.
片名：创始吸血鬼（第一季）